# TRACY PHAM

**Phone**: 0415 152 503 **Email**: tracyp161@gmail.com City/ Town: Melbourne, Vic, Australia

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tracyp161/ Portfolio: https://compassionate-ritchie-283757.netlify.app/

Github: https://github.com/tracy161

### **CAREER PROFILE**

An accomplished Frontend Developer with over three years of experience in web development in IT and construction industries. I am now looking for my next IT role as a MERN stack / React developer to go beyond in my profession. I am a very passionate developer who is always focusing on new technologies and willing to apply them to my work to go beyond the standard commitments and efficiently deliver large-scale projects to meet both company's and customer's expectations. I have a very strong and solid background in software development and a high ability to analyse and resolve complexity coding problems thanks to all my past experience. I also have deep understanding in web development patterns both in front-end and back-end, which allow me to smoothly handle all different stages of a project. I am a reliable team player with a focused attitude, especially in an agile team environment.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages: JavaScript(ES6), Node.JS, HTML5, CSS3, PHP

I am very confident in these programming languages which I have used to build multiple applications. Please refer to my portfolio for more information.

Web API: REST API, Apollo GraphQL

I have successfully integrated many different APIs into my applications using REST API and Apollo GraphQL, and I am very confident in building the back-end use of Node.JS, Express.JS, MongoDB, and Mongoose, the complete MERN Stack to provide RESTful API.

Libraries & Frameworks: React.JS, Redux/Redux-Thunk, SASS, Bootstrap, MaterializeCSS, React-Bootstrap, MaterialUI, Styled Components, Tailwind.

Database: MS SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDB.

Git Version Control, Cloud & Testing Tools: Github, Bitbucket, AWS(EC2, Route 53, Linux Server Setup), Jest, React Testing Library

#### SYSTEMS & APPLICATIONS

- Used different communication tools like Slack, Zoom, Skype, Microsoft Team.
- Being able to use different operating systems including Microsoft Windows, macOS, Linux, and their terminals.
- Highly skilled in Adobe Creative Suites such as Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign, After Effect.

#### QUALIFICATIONS & CERTIFICATIONS

Course	Institute	Year Completed
Certificate IT of Professional Year	Navitas Professional	2018
Bachelor of Information Technology	Melbourne Polytechnic	2017
Bachelor of Business	La Trobe University	2014

## CAREER SUMMARY

Role	Name of organisation	Year - Year
Frontend/ Full Stack Developer	Freelance	Mar 2019 - present
Digital Admin	Skyline Builders & Developers	Nov 2019 - Dec 2021
Web Developer Contractor	The Nova Group	Mar 2019 - Sep 2021
Web Development Intern	Psych Press	Dec 2017 - April 2018

#### RELEVANT CAREER HISTORY

## **Building Up My Portfolio**

2021 - present

Successfully building up my portfolio and including multiple projects which I have done in that.

### **Project 1: My Portfolio Website**

 A static website built by React to list all of my projects. Since it does not have a back-end, I handled its contact form by EmailJs to send viewers' inquiries directly to my email.

Link: https://compassionate-ritchie-283757.netlify.app/

## Project 2: Task Management App

A todo list app built by MERN STACK

Link: https://ancient-castle-24713.herokuapp.com/

• Project Details:

### Situation:

- This is an in-depth full stack todo list portal app to make users create productivity listing ongoing and complete tasks. There are a number of features from this app including:
- The ability for users to create, edit, delete and mark complete tasks.
- The ability for users to change their own username and password.
- User authentication: register and login
- User roles: admin and users
  - Admin can control other users: check all users and delete them if necessary
  - Admin can control the todo list tasks of other users and himself: check all the tasks created by users, delete the tasks if necessary
  - Able to see the total number of new tasks added and new user registered increasing every week

#### **Deliverables:**

- Build an extension backend API with Node.JS & Express.
- Protecting routes/endpoints with JWT (Json Web Token).
- Integrating React/ React Hooks with our Backend in an elegant way, creating a great workflow.
- Building our frontend to work with the API.
- Using Redux for App State Management, creating reducers, actions and components that integrate with Redux.
- Testing with Redux Chrome Extension.
- Creating Build Script, securing API keys and deploying to Heroku using Git.

#### Result:

- Completed all functionalities of a Todo List Portal App, user authentication and user roles.
- Match the design with theme provided (dashboard theme)
- Successfully run and deployed.

## **Project 3: Martin's Movies (REST API Integration)**

 A Movie Reviewing Web App using React hooks, Redux State Management & API Integration from The Movie Database

Link: https://martinsmovies123456.netlify.app/

## Project Details:

## Situation:

- Martin's Movies is a client who reviews movies online. They have moved all of their movies to an online movie database which is only accessible via an API. They need to:
  - build a new listing page to pull all data from their new database
  - allow customers to search by different movie Keyword
  - mark a movie as 'watched' so when they open the listing page again in the same browser it will still be marked as 'watched'
  - The App Design needs to be matched with the theme provided.

#### **Deliverables:**

- Use React.JS and React Hooks for building the App Frontend
- Integrate The Movie DB API
- Use Redux State Management creating reducers, actions and components that integrate with React.
- UI Design: React-Bootstrap.
- Testing with Redux Chrome Extension.
- Creating Build Script, securing API keys and deploying successfully to Netlify.

## Result:

Completed all functionalities as requested.

- Match the design with theme provided (dashboard theme)
- Successfully run and deployed.

## Project 4: Rick & Morty Characters (Apollo GraphQL API Integration)

- A React.JS application that displays characters from the Rick and Morty GraphQL API Link: https://quirky-varahamihira-05360b.netlify.app/
- Project Details

#### Situation:

- The App needs to display all characters in Rick and Morty show as followings:
  - List characters and display their name and image.
  - Allowing searching for characters based on their name.
  - Link each character to their details page
  - Character Details page: Display all characters information and all episodes that the characters in

#### **Deliverables:**

- Use React.JS for building the App Frontend
- Integrate Rick and Morty GraphQL API
- Configured Apollo Client that integrates Rick and Morty API with React.
- UI Design: Material UI v5.
- Create Unit Test for Character Details component using React Testing Library and Jest.
- Creating Build Script, securing API keys and deploying successfully to Netlify.

#### Result:

- Completed all functionalities as requested.
- Match the design with theme provided (dashboard theme)
- Successfully run and deployed.

## **Achievements**

- Frequently practice my programming skills through practical examples.
- Stay focused on new technologies in the IT industry.
- Growing technically in JavaScript Library, React.JS and Node.JS.
- Successfully implemented new features from written requirements to visible UI
- Successfully delivered projects in different timeframes.
- Strongly understanding of the project management process from start to finish and how to implement tasks from the beginning.

Web Developer The Nova Group Mar 2019 - Sep 2021

The Nova Group is a global media advertising agency providing digital strategy, tv & radio advertising, digital media, social listener platform, e-commerce web and mobile apps, CRM, content management, and customer experiences

#### Responsibilities

- Utilising JavaScript, React and PHP to build new features based on the requirements from senior developer and technical lead to create new functionality of applications.
- Building and improving features allocated by my team leader.
- Updating and optimising UI/UX using different react CSS libraries including React Bootstrap, Semantic React UI and in-line CSS.
- Developing front-end functionality of sites.
  - Produce both eCommerce and non-eCommerce creative layouts, contents and developments using CMS systems (Wordpress & Magento) for the use of clients.
  - Writing browser compliant HTML and Javascript.
  - Simultaneously managing several design projects. Contacting external webmasters to confirm links.
  - Provide guidance to team members on key issues.
- Maintain and manage websites including Wordpress & Magento Plugins, domain hostings, WHM configuration and DNS

## Project 1:

 Building a mini full stack social network application allowing users to connect with each other using PHP MVC Framework ( <a href="https://attitude.ferttil.com/">https://attitude.ferttil.com/</a>)

Project 2: This project is a Wordpress web design and development application for trading services

- Successfully followed to build from provided Figma/Photoshop designs
- Add a informative content and functions to the website
- Link: https://kitcomarkets.com/

### **Achievements**

- Successfully implement an application from start to finish, including all front-end, back-end, and deployment.
- Proficiently using Git and Github to code in a team with other team members.
- Managing application deployment on AWS and setting up its connection string to connect its database with its back-end.
- Strong understanding of the project management process and how to implement tasks in a development team.
- Responsive design, perform best practices for UI and UX. Especially in an eCommerce context.
- Implement SEO in regard to page performance by enhancing up to 50%.
- Responsible for working on a range of projects, designing appealing websites and interacting on a daily basis with clients and marketers.
- Enhancing my PHP skills significantly since I need to use different styles of MVC frameworks to work with different legacy codes.

## Web Dev/Administrator Skyline Builders & Developers

Mar 2019 - Dec 2021

Skyline is a Melbourne based construction and consulting group that provides digital strategy in building world-class responsive websites for businesses of all sizes across Australia.

## **Responsibilities**

- Responsible for the design and development of websites with day to day support for every functionality of the website in Construction. Hospitality Industries.
- Implementing business requirements for Skyline Showroom from frontend, backend to database design while keeping a timeline with product managers. Looking after the overall architecture of Skyline Showroom while supporting other developers to complete their tasks. Collaborating with other teams to develop the Skyline website and features across the network.

#### **Achievements**

- Developed and now took over the ownership of the development of the entire Skyline website with end to end functionalities from frontend, backend and deployment work. Skyline is developed using Wordpress, Javascript (ES6 and Jquery), Css/Sass with PHP patterns to communicate with backend Web Apis and data services.
- Designed and developed several types of construction projects within Skyline team such as On-going, Completed and Planning Projects.
- Managing application deployment on GitHub and setting up its connection string to connect its database with its back-end.
- Responsive design, perform best practices for UI and UX.
- Implement SEO in regard to page performance
- Collaborating with DevOp Developers for website and email hosting troubleshooting.